阿尔布开克警察  你好
Albuquerque Police. Hello.
先生  我们想跟你谈谈
Sir, we'd like to talk with you for a minute.
你能开下门吗
Could you open the door, please?
我们知道你在里面
Look, we know you're in there.
从猫眼里都能看到你的影子
You're casting a shadow through your peephole.
我们只想谈谈
All we want to do is talk.
你能开下门吗
Would you please open the door?
还是算了吧  警官
I'd, I'd prefer not to, officers.
先生  请开门
Sir, come on and open up.
我情况特殊
I have a condition.
我不能出门
I can't go outside
或者暴露在外界环境中
or be exposed to what's out there.
可你都出门偷邻居报纸了
You were able to come outside to steal your neighbor's newspaper.
我没偷啊
I didn't steal it.
我留了五美金
I left $5.
标价才五十美分啊
The, the cover price is 50 cents.
你的邻居同意把报纸卖给你了吗
Did your neighbor consent to sell you her paper?
我
I...
她  这
She -- i-isn't --
警官  让我们
L-- um, officer, let's -- let's --
来谈谈一个叫"合理根据"的东西
Let's talk about something called "Probable cause."
警察有权逮捕的根据
你们肯定知道  在新墨西哥州
As I'm sure you know, in the state of New Mexico,
有一个两部分的测试
there is a two-part test
来决定警官是否有
to determine whether police officers
客观上合理的依据...
have an objectively reasonable basis...
在对亚利桑那州的诉讼中
...the situation a-as missing,
该情况是缺失的
versus Arizona,
正如我指出的  造成一个后果...
as I pointed out creates an event...
汤米  过来看看
Hey, Tommy. Come around here, would you?
这就是为什么第十巡回上诉法庭
A-and that's why the 10th circuit court of appeals
判了强制令...
ruled that a coercive order...
看看这个
Check this out.
要求一个人离开自己家无异于抓捕
...requiring an individual leave his house is seizure...
因此
...and, therefore,
禁止无理搜查和扣押
我受第四修正案的保护  不是吗
protected under the Fourth Amendment, right?
都是便携炉用的燃料
Whole lot of camp-stove fuel.
他简直就像个神经病
Guy sure as shit sounds like a tweaker.
你看到他的电路盒了吗
You see what he did to the breaker box?
他出来  还是我们进去
Is he coming out, or are we going in?
你有十秒钟的时间开门
You got 10 seconds to open this door,
不然我们会破门而入  你听到了吗
or it's coming down. You hear me?
这是最后的警告
Final warning!
我让你们进来
Okay, I'll-I'll let you in,
但你们得把所有的电子设备都留在外面
but you have to leave your electronic devices outside.
手机  对讲机
No phones, no walkie-talkies,
手电筒
no flashlights--
电击枪更不能带进来
definitely, definitely no tasers.
这个最为关键  行吗
I can't emphasize that enough. Deal?
我会把报纸还回去的
Or, look, look. I'll give the paper back.
绝命律师
第一季 第五集
谁
Yeah?
詹姆斯·麦吉尔来拜访理查德·赛普斯
James McGill to see Mr. Richard Sipes.
里基  叫我里基就好
Ricky, call me "Ricky."
进来吧
Come on in.
这是我助理的车
This is my assistant's car.
我的奔驰还在店里维修
Well, my Mercedes is in the shop.
看来我得给他涨工资了  你说得对
I ought to give him a raise. You're right.
吉米  我在电视上看到你了
Jim, I saw you on the TV--
广告牌风云
that billboard thing.
我发现了两个闪光点
And I had me a pair of insights.
第一个闪光点
Insight the first--
你不怕舍身救人
you ain't afraid to put yourself out there.
第二个闪光点
And insight the second,
你相信真正的美国精神
you believe in the real America--
自由自在  自给自足
freedom, self-sufficiency.
我相信  我真的相信
I do. I-I really do.
当我看到像你这样的人
When I see a man like you
开着那辆烂车
driving that foreign shitbox of a car...
那辆车其实是
Well, see, actually, it's--
说明这年头  好人没有好报
It's a sign a good man can't get ahead today.
真是荒谬至极
It's a damned travesty. That's what it is.
也许是这样  里基
Well, that may be, Ricky,
但是
but...
我不认为自己是个受害者
I refuse to consider myself a victim.
历史再一次重演了
You know, we are once again at a point in our history
政府那苍蝇拍一样的大手
where the fly-swatting hand of government
正在扼杀企业家的自由灵魂
is crushing the spirit of entrepreneurship --
税收  职业安全与健康管理局的要求
Taxes, OSHA requirements,
国新社用肥大的鼻子嗅着每一个雇员的动作
the I.N.S. poking their big, fat nose into every mother-loving hire.
这是赤裸裸的压迫
It's damned oppressive.
很不幸
It's tragic.
这是非美国式的
It's un-American.
吉米  我认为你就是我所需要的律师
Jim, I think you are just the lawyer I need,
因为我的案子很大  是个大案子
'cause I got me a case -- major -- I say, a major case.
你准备好腾出时间了吗
Are you ready to clear your calendar?
里基  我洗耳恭听
Ricky, I'm all ears.
我要脱离美利坚合众国
I want to secede from the United States.
如今我在这里有4.4平方公里的房产
Now, I got 1,100 acres of property here,
用太阳能和井水可以自给自足
self-sustaining with solar power and wells,
不受垄断条令约束的主权国
a sovereign state immune to the business-killing regulations
虽在美国地理范围内却不受管制
of the country in which it geographically lies.
我们要成为美国的梵蒂冈城
We are going to be America's Vatican City.
里基
Ricky...
我跟你干
I'm your man.
好啊  我们开始吧
Yeah, let's do this.
让我们做给他们看
Let's show 'em all.
是的  我们就要这样做
Yes! We are doing this!
可是这条路不会一帆风顺的
Now, it's not gonna be easy, sir.
政府会跟我们展开恶战
I mean, the government is gonna fight us tooth and nail.
最后我们可能会上最高法院
We could end up in the Supreme Court --
这可能要花费数千工时
I'm talking thousands of man-hours --
经过数年的努力
I mean, years of effort.
你准备好了吗
Are you ready for that?
我吗
Me?
让他们放马过来吧
I say bring 'em on.
我们开诚布公地说吧
Let's talk turkey.
你的收费标准是多少
What's your rate?
每小时四百五十元
$450 an hour.
不按小时算
The hell with hourly.
直接付定金
I want you on retainer.
一百万怎么样
How about $1 million even --
预付五十万  搞定后再付另一半
$500,000 up front and $500,000 when we're done?
一百万
A million?
听起来  很公平
That seems...fair.
你愿意收现金吗
Would you like that in cash?
免税而且有桑迪亚共和国的
Tax-free and backed by the full faith and credit
十足信用作为担保
of the sovereign Sandia Republic.
这是...
It's, uh...
小子  你占尽了先机啊
Son...you are getting in on the ground floor.
麦吉尔先生你好
Mr. McGill, hi.
感谢你的到来
Thanks so much for coming.
我是罗兰·杰科克斯  叫我罗兰
Roland Jaycocks. Roland.
罗兰  认识你很高兴
Hey, Roland. Great to meet you.
你可以叫我吉米
You can call me "Jimmy."
吉米  当然了
Jimmy, absolutely.
你好  请进
Hello. Please, come on in.
谢谢你
Well, thank you.
天呐  爬那个广告板是什么感觉
God, what was it like climbing that billboard?
一定很吓人吧
Must have been pretty scary, huh?
那个人需要帮助  仅此而已
Guy needed help -- that's all.
其实我做的事  别人也都能做
You know, if I could do it, anybody could.
我很佩服你
Well, my hat is off to you.
就是这里了
So, here we are.
专利法是不是你...
And patent law is something you --
是的  实际上我接过很多专利案件
Oh, yeah. In fact, I-I do so many patent cases,
我以后专接专利案件得了
I should probably just go ahead and specialize already.
这是什么
So, what do we got?
-我有个不情之请  -请说
- I feel silly asking this. - Yeah.
在我向你展示我的发明之前
But before I show you my invention,
你介不介意签署一份保密协议
would you mind signing a non-disclosure agreement?
当然可以  没问题
You got it. No problem.
这是我毕生的心血
It's my idea of a lifetime.
万一费雪或者孩之宝得知了这个想法...
If Fisher-Price or Playskool ever got their hands on this...
美国玩具商
无需担心
No worries.
准备好了吗
You ready?
我以前好像看过这样的东西
I may have seen one of these before.
和这个不一样
Not like this.
我在这上面加了个小装置
This one has this little unit I've added.
这才是我的发明
This is my invention.
-你有孩子吗  -没有
- Do you have children? - No.
我和我妻子有两个男孩  一个四岁一个六岁
My wife and I have two boys -- 4 and 6.
说真的  教他们学会上厕所
And let me tell you -- toilet-training them?
真是场噩梦  两个都是
Nightmare, both times.
他们不习惯用坐便器
They just didn't want to use the commode.
所以我在传感器上连了一个语音芯片
So I wired a motion sensor to a voice chip,
没必要说得那么专业
and, well, no sense getting all technical,
关键就是正强化
but it's all about positive reinforcement.
通过鼓励使一行为形成
这就是"如厕好伙伴托尼"
Meet Tony the toilet buddy.
当你坐下去准备上厕所
And when you sit down to do your business,
它是这样工作的
this is how he works.
对  就是这样
Oh, yeah, that's the way!
天呐  好大
Gosh, you're big!
你真大
You're so big!
天呐  你真棒
My goodness! Look at you!
快把我塞满  钱德勒
Fill me up, Chandler!
快放进来
Put it in me!
钱德勒是我的小儿子  他很喜欢
Chandler's my youngest -- loves it.
快给我  钱德勒  我想要
Give it to me, Chandler! I want it all!
后面还有呢
Anyway, it goes on from there.
不过大致就这样
You get the picture.
没错  我...
Yeah, I, uh...
是的
Yeah.
那么你觉得怎么样
So, what do you think?
这是不是太挑逗了
It's a little sexual, maybe?
挑逗  你是什么意思...
Sexual? What -- what does that...
带有某种暗示  可能
Suggestive, maybe --
可能这种说法比较合适
Maybe that's a better word.
听着  我并没有
Look, I'm not --
我不是说这个发明不会让你发财
I'm not saying this thing won't make you rich.
有些环太平洋国家的富人
I mean, some of your wealthier Pacific rim nations --
那帮变态疯子  他们会爱死这个的
They'll love this -- the crazy bastards.
这项发明是面向孩子的  孩子  明白吗
I created this for children -- children, understand?
伟哥起初还是用来治疗高血压的呢
Viagra was originally invented to treat hypertension.
结果呢
Look how that turned out.
你真是叫人作呕
You're completely disgusting, you know that?!
伙计  你才是发明性爱马桶的人
Hey, buddy, you're the one with the sex toilet.
马上滚出我家
Get off my property!
对了
Hey, you know what?
我真心希望你能大赚一笔
I hope you do make a fortune,
然后用这笔钱给钱德勒做心理治疗吧
'cause Chandler's gonna need it to help pay for his therapy!
邻里联合对抗犯罪
我找到了阿尔卑斯牧童
I found the Alpine Shepherd boy!
不  你就坐那儿
No, no. You just stay put.
我这就过去
I'll be right over.
我们说到哪儿了
Now, where were we?
再来点茶吧
Oh, would you like some more tea?
不  谢谢  不用了
No! No, thank you. I'm -- I'm fine.
那么牧羊少年赫梅尔
Now, the shepherd boy Hummel --
是要留给你的侄子克拉伦斯吗
That's gonna go to your nephew Clarence?
-只要他能念完大学  -好的
- As long as he finishes college. - Okay.
如果他辍学  那就留给我的侄女雷琳
If he drops out, it goes to my niece Raylene.
但雷琳就得不到那个姑娘...
But then, Raylene doesn't get the girl --
那个养鹅姑娘
The girl with the geese.
那就留给你的表亲海伦
Yeah. No, then that would go to your cousin Helen...
条件是她不和弗雷德里克复婚对吗
...so long as she never remarries Frederick?
-没错  -好的
- Exactly. - Yeah.
还有这对黄发双胞胎瓷人
And no matter what, I want the towheaded twins
我无论如何要留给劳伦斯教士的孙子
to go to Reverend Lawrence's grandson.
你是说黑尼斯教士吗
Um, don't you mean Reverend Hanes?
因为要留给劳伦斯教士孙子的
'Cause Reverend Lawrence's grandson is going to get
是这个吹笛天使  他是唱诗班的
the, uh, Lute-playing angel, 'cause he was in the choir.
脑子转得真快  麦吉尔先生
Very sharp, Mr. McGill.
我还以为律师都是傻瓜呢
And here I thought all lawyers were idiots.
一半是傻瓜
No, only half of us are idiots.
剩下的一半都是骗子
The other half are crooks.
你真风趣
Aren't you a spicy one?
要是我再年轻四十岁
If I were 40 years younger,
我肯定会要你请我喝一杯果汁朗姆酒
I'd have you buy me a Pina colada.
如果你让我起草一份放弃急救同意书
Well, if you want me to draw up a DNR,
我就带上搅拌机和菠萝
I'll bring a blender and some pineapple.
当我在电视上看到
I knew I'd like you
你是如何英勇救人的时候我就喜欢上你了
when I saw how you saved that poor man on the television.
世风日下  勇气已经很少见了
Moxie is in such short supply these days.
没错
Yeah.
我也很以自己的勇气为荣
Well, I pride myself on my moxie.
虽然我不想这样
Now, I hate to do this,
但我必须得说一下我的报酬问题
but I do need to bring up my payment.
很抱歉
Um and I'm sorry,
绿色盾牌邮票  由S&H公司发售
集齐一套可兑换公司产品
我不接受绿色盾牌邮票作为支付方式
but I can't accept S&H green stamps.
我一共要收取您一百四十块
Now, uh, my fee is $140.
一百四
$140?
您可以今天先给我七十块
I'll gladly accept $70 today.
等我把所有文件都准备好以后
And $70 when I come back
再把剩下的七十块给我
with the completed documents, if...
二十  四十  六十
$20, $40, $60...
八十  一百
$80, $100...
一百二  一百四
And $20, $40.
好的
Uh. Okay.
麦吉尔先生  我们能继续了吗
Shall we continue, Mr. McGill?
当然了  我们继续  施特劳斯太太
Yes. Yes, we shall, Mrs. Strauss.
要涂在指甲上  别蹭到皮上
Put it on the nail, not the skin.
你的脚趾这么小  我也没办法
I can't help it if your toes are too small.
如果都长得一样大
They should all be the same size --
都像大脚趾一样
the size of the big toe.
那我就好办了
That one I can do.
是啊  那样看起来才迷人
Yeah, that would be attractive.
你今天怎么样
So... how's it go again?
钱德勒  你好大噢
Oh, you're huge, Chandler!
你真是个大家伙
You're a big, big boy!
还这么长
Oh, where does it end?!
别停啊  钱德勒
Oh, don't stop, Chandler!
别停
Don't stop!
哎呦  来了来了
Oh, here it comes!
那是什么啊
Oh, what is that?
-那是一粒玉米吗  -你别说了
- Is that a piece of corn? - No, don't.
你是不是吃玉米了  钱德勒
Did you eat corn, Chandler?
-不会是玉米吧  钱德勒  -真恶心
- Is that a niblet I see, Chandler? - That's disgusting.
-求你别讲了  -你受不了了吗
- No, don't. - Too much?
就是这么有趣
Hey, good times.
你的生活就是再糟糕
Oh. Even your lousy days
也比我那些好日子有趣
are more interesting than my good ones.
是吗  那我们可得想办法改变一下了
Yeah, well, we should definitely do something about that.
说真的  你将来可千万别这样过活
Seriously, don't ever try to make a living at this.
好好干你的律师吧
Stick with the law.
是啊  因为只有在法律这一行里
Yeah, because I'm really...
我才能做出点颠覆世界的事
lighting the world on fire in that department.
你今天办理了两份遗嘱吗
Did two wills today?
没错  还帮人起草了一份生前信托
Two wills, and I started a living trust.
老头老太太可待见我了
Whoopee! Old people love me.
也许你可以考虑去做老年法律师
Maybe you got a future in Elder law.
你觉得我能行吗
You think I could handle all that glamour?
我可是认真的
No, I'm serious.
我自己也想做
I-I've thought about getting into Elder law myself.
我奶奶快不行的时候  我就在一旁看着
I watched my grandmother at the end.
简直
It's...
简直太可怕  不得不和保险公司周旋
It's awful what people have to deal with -- insurance companies.
我那些混蛋堂兄弟偷了她的存款和止痛药
My scumbag cousins stealing her savings and her pain meds.
人老了很悲惨
Getting old sucks.
老年人需要有人支持
Seniors need someone on their side.
是霍华德
It's Howard.
他到底要干嘛
What the hell does he want?
霍华德
Hi, Howard.
没有  我是说我还没...
Uh, no. I mean, I haven't, uh...
天哪  什么时候
Oh, my god. When?
好的
Yeah, okay.
我看我能不能找到吉米
I'll see if I can, um, track Jimmy down.
我会打给你的  没问题
I'll call you back. S-sure.
你哥出事了
It's Chuck.
查克
Chuck.
查克  能听到我说话吗
Chuck, you with me?
查克  是我啊
Chuck, hey, buddy. It's me.
你能说话吗
Hey, can you talk to me?
老天啊  真是帮混蛋
Jesus Christ. These sons of bitches.
先生  快停下
Hey, hey. Sir, you can't do that.
-所有设备都得开着  -不行  不能有电
- All of this needs to stay on. - No, no. No electricity.
你明白吗
You understand?
不行  设备必须得开着  我叫保安了
No, it needs to be on. I'm getting security.
你别去  等等
No, uh, wait, wait.
你等等  别去  等等啊
Wait, wait. Uh, no. Wait, wait, wait, wait.
那盏怎么没关
Huh? Why isn't that one going out?
-吉米  吉米  -去死吧
- Jimmy. Jimmy. - Damn it.
吉米  等下  吉米  冷静
I just -- Jimmy, wait a second. Jimmy. Think.
-你想干嘛  -先生  先生
- What's the plan here? - Sir? Sir?
先生  请你下来
Sir, I need you to get down from there.
你们这是酷刑室吗
What the hell kind of torture chamber you running here?
他对电流过敏  知道吗
He -- he's allergic to electricity, all right?
你听到医生说的了  快下来
You heard the doc. Get down now.
不  这些灯还有机器
No, all these lights and machines --
你还不如直接把他扔进微波炉里
you might as well throw him into a microwave.
-快下来  -别碰我
- Come on down now. - No, don't touch me!
他是病人的弟弟  请听他说
He is this patient's brother. Please, listen to him.
-我们走  -等下
- Hey, let's go. - Hey. Wait.
等一下  埃德温
Hold on a second, Edwin.
先生  你平静下来了吗
Sir, are you ready to calm down now?
是的  他叫吉米  并且他会平静下来的
Yes. His name is Jimmy, and, yes, he is gonna calm down.
我需要你亲口说  吉米
I need you to say the words, Jimmy.
我需要听你说
I need to hear it from you.
我很平静  好吗  平静
I'm calm, okay? I'm calm.
埃德温  你到走廊去等好吗
Edwin, why don't you go wait in the hallway?
需要的话我会叫你
I'll call if we need you.
好了  跟我说说电流的事儿
Okay, so, tell me about the electricity.
听着  我知道这听起来很荒谬  但是真的
Yeah, look, I know how it sounds, but it's real.
该死
Oh, shit.
我的手机和其它有电池的东西
My phone and stuff -- anything with a battery in it --
都不能靠近他
he can't have it near him.
等一下
Hang on.
-这是我的手机  -好了  这就行了
- Here's my phone. - Okay, that's it.
谢谢
Thanks.
好了  到底发生什么了
Okay, what the hell happened to him?
他为什么在这里
Why is he here?
很明显  查尔斯偷了邻居报纸
Apparently, it started when Charles stole his neighbor's newspaper.
什么  他从来不离开房子
What? He -- he never leaves the house.
我不知道所有的细节
I don't -- I don't have all the details,
但警察找到他时他非常激动
but the police found him in a very agitated state.
具有很强的攻击性并且语无伦次
He was confrontational and incoherent.
你怎么不给我打电话
How come you didn't call me?
我为什么要从我哥哥的
Uh, why did I have to hear about this
混蛋律师合伙人那里听到这些
through my brother's prick of a law partner?
我们找到的唯一联系方式
The only contact information we could find
是一张名片
was a business card.
吉米  我的意见是  查尔斯需要住院
Jimmy, in my opinion, Charles should be committed
进行三十天的精神科观察
for 30 days of psychiatric observation.
作为家庭成员
As a family member,
你可以为他提交评估申请
you can submit a petition for him to be evaluated.
拉斯克鲁塞斯有家非常好的机构
There's an excellent facility in Las Cruces.
他明天就可以去
He can be there tomorrow.
我还是不去了
I'd rather not.
伙计  我在这儿呢
Hey, buddy. Hey, I'm right here.
查克
Oh, hey, Chuck.
抱歉
Excuse me.
麦吉尔先生  我是克鲁兹医生
Mr. McGill, My name is Dr. Cruz.
你知道你为什么在医院吗
Do you know why you're in the hospital?
警察强行进入  没有搜查证  没有理由
The police kicked in my door -- no warrant, no cause.
我没有语无伦次
I wasn't incoherent.
只是他们不愿听我说
They just weren't listening.
他们用了电击枪  吉米
They tasered me, Jimmy.
天哪
Aw, jesus.
金
Kim?
对不起  我回避下
I'm sorry. I can give you privacy.
不不不  没事儿的  留下来
Oh, no, no, no. That's all right. Stay.
霍华德给我打电话
Howard...called me.
他很担心你
He's very concerned about you.
你现在感觉怎么样  麦吉尔先生
How are you feeling now, Mr. McGill?
你有手机或是传呼机吗
Uh, do -- do you have a phone or a -- a pager,
任何装有电池的东西
anything with a battery?
我觉得没有了  我
I don't think so. I...
是啊
Yeah.
一时疏忽  抱歉
Oversight. Sorry about that.
你能跟我说说你现在的情况吗
Can you tell me a little more about your...situation?
这不是什么情况
It's not a situation.
这是一种病症
It's a condition --
电磁过敏症
electromagnetic hypersensitivity.
由于不明原因  我的神经系统
For reasons unknown, my nervous system has become sensitized
对特定频率的电磁辐射变得非常敏感
to certain frequencies of electromagnetic radiation.
你弟弟说你对电流过敏
Your brother called it an allergy to electricity.
有点过度简化了
Well, it's an oversimplification,
但基本上是正确的
but it's essentially correct.
电子设备会产生相应的电磁场
Electronic devices create their own electromagnetic fields.
我越是接近这种设备  我的症状就越严重
The closer I am to such devices, the worse my symptoms.
什么症状
Which are?
皮肤灼烧感
Burning sensation on my skin,
骨头里又冷得刺骨
a sharp, cold pain in my bones,
肌肉酸痛  心悸
muscle fatigue, heart palpitations,
视线模糊  耳鸣
blurred vision, tinnitus,
眩晕  恶心  呼吸急促
vertigo, nausea, shortness of breath,
-总的来说...  -很难受
- a general -- - It hurts.
没错  很难受
Yes, it hurts.
你什么时候开始出现这种症状的
When did you first experience these symptoms?
肯定是...
Oh, it must have been...
你一年半以前离开公司的
Y-you left the office 18 months ago.
既然这样  那肯定有两年了
Huh. Well, in that case, uh, must have been almost two years.
两年
Two years?
那你也算是忍了很久了
That's a -- that's a long time to live with discomfort.
又来了
Oh, there it is.
你觉得我疯了
You think I'm crazy.
我没这么说
I never said that.
你是没说  因为你很有礼貌
No, you didn't, because you're very polite,
但你是这么想的
but you think it.
不然你不会跟我提什么送精神病院
Otherwise, you wouldn't be talking about commitment.
你不喜欢谈论那个吗
You find that idea distressing.
谁他妈会喜欢
Who the hell wouldn't?
我觉得这样对待一个
I -- I find it inappropriate
肉体上遭受折磨的人实在是太不人道了
for a person suffering from a physical condition.
只要跟我多待段时间
Anyone who's spent more than a few minutes with me
就会知道这不是我的幻觉
knows that this isn't some kind of delusion.
你同意吗  金
Wouldn't you agree, Kim?
她当然同意
Of course she does.
我又不是医生
Well, I'm not a doctor.
你都认识我快十年了
You've known me for the better part of a decade.
你见过我表现出任何征兆
Have you ever seen me exhibit any sign --
任何精神疾病的征兆吗
any sign whatsoever of mental illness?
看到没
See?
如果我觉得你能治好我
I-if I thought for one second you could cure me,
相信我  我绝对会把握这个机会
believe me, I'd jump at the chance.
但恕我冒犯
But with all due respect,
找精神病医生是行不通的
psychiatry doesn't have the answers.
我愿意一试
I'd very much like to try.
第43章第一条第十一点  E13部分
Section 43-1-11, part E13.
"入院申请要与病人的
"The proposed commitment is consistent with
"实际治疗需求相吻合
"the treatment needs of the client
并且要避免采取极端手段"
and with the least drastic means principle."
你们觉得让我忍受这种痛苦一个月
Do you think subjecting me to this kind of pain for a month
不算是极端手段吗
is the least drastic means?
还不如把他扔到削木机里一个月
He might as well spend a month in a wood chipper.
我知道你很难受  真的
I understand your frustration. I do.
你显然头脑非常清楚
You're obviously a highly intelligent man
只是身体状况不如人意
in difficult circumstances.
我能问你个问题吗  只是我个人好奇
May I ask you a question, just for my own interest?
你怎么解决你的一些日常需要呢
How do you meet the needs of daily life?
要照明怎么办呢
What do you do for light, or...
或者怎么准备食物
how do you prepare food?
我用无铅汽油灯
I use white-gas lanterns.
煮饭的话我有个便携炉
For cooking, I have a camp stove.
我还有个冷却器  要不停往里面加冰块
I have a large cooler I keep filled with ice.
虽然不好用  但还凑合
It's not ideal, but I make do.
我知道了
I see.
谢谢
Well, thank you.
如果你不介意的话
Would you mind if I took a moment
我能和你弟弟谈谈吗
to speak with your brother?
谈完后确认下你的钱包还在自己身上
Oh, uh, make sure you still have your wallet when you're done.
真好笑
Funny guy.
吉米
Jimmy.
我想回家
I want to go home.
这招太损了
That was a dirty trick.
那不是什么花招  是为了证实
That wasn't a trick -- it was a demonstration.
他对电流不过敏
This allergy to electricity isn't real --
只是某种深层情绪的表达
It's a manifestation of something deeper.
我没说百分百是真的  好吗
I'm not saying it's 100% real, okay?
但是查克比咱们俩加起来都聪明
But Chuck is smarter than you and me put together,
所以没办法说服他
so we're not talking him out of this,
我也不会让他住到橡胶室[治疗精神病]里
and I'm not sending him to a rubber room.
没人说要送到橡胶室
No one is talking about rubber rooms.
有专家能...
There are specialists who will --
他看过专家了
He's seen specialists, okay?
这里到丹佛最好的医生都看过
The best doctors from here to Denver,
没人能帮得上忙  谁也不行
and none of them helped -- not one.
所以你是打算放弃了吗
So you're ready to give up.
谁要放弃了
Who's giving up, huh?
一直是我在照顾他好吗
I'm -- I'm the one doing the heavy lifting here.
他说的无铅汽油灯--
That white gas he was talking about --
你觉得是谁给他的
who do you think brings him that?
还有牛奶  面包  厕纸
And milk and bread and toilet paper
冰块  他的一切必需品
and ice and every other damn thing he needs.
你是在帮他还是纵容他
Is that helping or enabling?
如果你在监护权听证会上作证
If you testify in a custodial hearing,
他就能得到需要的帮助  你有能力这么做
he can get the help he needs -- that's in your power.
非自愿被送入精神病院
To be committed involuntarily,
他必须对自己或他人构成威胁
he has to be a danger to himself or others.
他确实很危险
And he is.
室内用科勒曼汽油灯  便携炉
Coleman lanterns indoors, a camp stove?
他有可能把房子烧了
I mean, he could burn his house down
甚至把整个小区都烧着
or the entire neighborhood,
到时候他就得在精神病院呆十几二十年了
and then you're looking at a commitment of 10 to 20 years.
要是
What if --
要是他在家中伤了他自己怎么办
What if he just hurts himself in a household accident?
他怎么呼救
How does he call for help?
你有能力帮助你哥哥
You have the power to help your brother --
给他真正的帮助
truly help him.
你逃避不了这个现实
Ignoring this won't make it go away.
要是你你会怎么做
What would you do?
我只知道
All I know is...
他需要帮助
he needs help.
放了他
Untie him.
我要带他走
I'm getting him out of here.
护士会把出院登记表拿给你
A nurse will bring you the release forms.
总算来了
Oh, boy.
-吉米  吉米  -我找到他了
- Jimmy. Jimmy. - I found him.
我觉得我应该等你来
I thought I'd wait till you got here.
太好了  他怎么样了
Great. How's he doing?
好多了  正在休息
Better. Resting.
那就好
Good.
那个  吉米...
Uh, Jimmy...
我已经和地检官谈过了
I want you to know that I've talked to the D.A.,
他绝对不会在任何入院书上签字的
and he absolutely will not sign off on any commitment papers.
这是身体问题  不是精神上的问题
This is a physical condition, not a mental one.
查克心智很健全
Chuck is of sound mind.
在这一点上我们应该能达成一致
I think we can all agree on that.
你干得真好啊  霍华德
You're a real peach, Howard.
你当然不希望查克被送进精神病院
Of course you don't want Chuck committed.
是啊  我是不希望  我为什么希望
No, I don't. Why would I?
因为如果查克入院了
Because if Chuck were committed,
我就会成为他的法定监护人
then I'd become his legal guardian,
就可以让他从律所撤股了
and I cash him out of HHM.
天哪  吉米  你确定
Jesus, Jimmy. Now?
他还躺在那里  你真的要谈这个吗
You want to hash that out while he's lying in here?
日光浴床肯定把你脑子烧坏了
You know, the tanning bed must have melted your brain
如果你花一秒钟想一想
If you think for one second --
伙计们  我们的重点应该是查克
Guys -- Chuck. That's why we're here.
对  别跑题
Yes. Let's stay on point.
我们是在谈论一个人的健康问题
We're talking about the well-being of a man
我们都很爱他
whom we all love very much.
问题是有点复杂
There's many factors at play.
但请勿夹杂恶意
Spite doesn't have to be one of them.
知道吗  霍华德
You know what, Howard?
你没来之前我还在犹豫
I was on the fence till you showed up,
多谢你帮我做了决定
but thanks for helping me decide.
跟你的摇钱树说拜拜吧
Wave bye-bye to your cash cow,
因为你马上就会失去它了
'cause it's leaving the pasture.
我这就送他入院
I'm committing him.
吉米  等一下
Jimmy. Uh, J-- wait.
吉米  等等  吉米
Jimmy, wait. Jimmy.
吉米  等一下好吗
Jimmy, can you wait?
吉米  等等
Jimmy, wait a second.
听着  我知道查克需要帮助
Listen, I agree that Chuck needs help,
也许你确实应该这样做
and maybe it's the right thing to do,
但是你不能采取这种方式
but you can't do it like this.
我就想让那个杂种着急
I just want to see that son of a bitch sweat.
明眼人一看就知道他怕什么
It's so obvious what he's afraid of.
我要带我哥回家了
I'm taking my brother home.
到这边来  老哥
There you go, buddy.
这边
Yeah. There you go.
注意台阶  一步  两步
Okay, some steps. One and two.
往这边
And there you go.
你回家了
Hey, you're home, all right?
会没事的
Everything's gonna be all right.
想吃点东西吗
Uh, you want something to eat --
喝茶  喝杯茶吗
Uh, some tea -- a cup of tea?
-咖啡  -行
- Coffee? - Yeah.
咖啡  那就咖啡了
Coffee. Coffee it is.
吉米  我要我的...
Uh, Jimmy, I'm -- I'm -- I'm gonna need my...
我不...
I don't -- I-I-I-I...
它在...
Oh, it's...
行
Yeah.
想聊聊这事吗
You want to talk about this?
-没什么好聊的  -你拿了报纸
- There's nothing to talk about. - You took the paper.
你看到了
You saw this.
然后犯病了
You got sick.
你什么意思
What's your point?
查克  你犯病是因为看到这则新闻了吧
Chuck, I think you got sick 'cause you saw this story.
每次你觉得我做了坏事
No, w-- whenever you think I've done something wrong,
可疑的事  病情就更严重
something questionable, you get worse.
我犯病
I didn't get sick
不是因为看到你上了报纸
because I read about you in the paper.
我犯病
I got sick
是因为我出门取报纸
because I went out of my house to retrieve the paper.
我好累  不想吵了  吉米
I'm too tired for this argument, Jimmy.
都吵过那么多次了
I-I've had it too many times.
你以为我又变回风流吉米了
You think this is the return of Slippin' Jimmy,
-但其实没有  -好吧
- but it's not. - All right.
你觉得广告牌的事不道德
Uh, you think the billboard thing was unethical,
但这是...宣传
but it was...promotion.
这是广告  仅此而已
It was advertising -- that's all.
贝茨对亚利桑那州律师协会案  允许律师公开打广告的首个修正案
在贝茨对亚利桑那州律师协会一案中
Which wasn't even allowed until five supreme court justices
五位大法官发了疯才允许律师打广告
went completely bonkers in Bates vs. State Bar of Arizona.
但不管怎样
But in any event...
这是合法的
it's legal.
你想打广告是你自己的事[生意]
If you want to advertise, that's your business.
"生意"是个关键词  查克
"Business" being the operative word there, Chuck,
因为打广告才有生意
because I-I have gotten business off of this --
合法的生意  订立遗嘱  接受委托
legit business -- wills, uh, trusts.
我开始专攻老年法案子
Uh, I'm -- I'm kind of starting to specialize in Elder law.
老年法
Elder law?
是  老年人要处理的事
Yeah, the things the elderly have to deal with --
比如亲戚觊觎他们的存款
I mean, you know, relatives coming after their savings,
电话推销员  反向抵押贷款诈骗
telemarketers, reverse-mortgage scams --
人老了很悲惨
I mean, getting old sucks.
老年人需要有人支持  所以...
Seniors need someone on their side, so...
我就是那个支持他们的人
You're looking at him.
听起来很...
Well, that sounds...
有前途
promising.
但跟我的病情没什么关系
But it has nothing to do with my condition.
查克  听我说  我现在向你承诺  行吗
Chuck, listen. I'm gonna make you a promise right now, okay?
不用  没必要  不强求
No, not necessary, not requested.
行
Okay.
广告牌的事就这一次
The billboard was a one-time thing.
我是名好律师
I-I-I'm a good lawyer.
我只是需要点噱头
I just needed some razzmatazz, you know,
一些技巧  才能行动起来
to get the ball rolling, some showmanship --
仅此而已
That's all it was.
不会有下次了
It's done now. It's over.
好吧
All right.
从今以后  我要规规矩矩
From here on out, I'm gonna play by the rules.
律师都该这样
As any lawyer should.
没错
Exactly.
有很多委托人需要我
There are clients out there who need me,
我会竭尽所能给他们
and I'm gonna give them the best representation
最好的代理
I know how to provide.
我要光明磊落  行吗
I-I'm on the up-and-up, okay?
我会改过
I will be good.
风流吉米
Slippin' Jimmy --
早就死在了西塞罗市
He's back in Cicero, dead and buried.
好
Okay.
我们走着瞧
We'll see.
你去哪儿
Where you going?
总得有人煮咖啡啊
Somebody's got to make that coffee.
一定会真相大白的
I'm sure the truth will come out,
如果我们都希望得知真相
if, indeed, that's what we're all interested in.
我知道在座各位
I know everybody in this courtroom
对尼古拉斯男爵的过去深表同情
has strong feelings about Nicholas Baron's past,
但我认为他并非因为自己的过去而受审
but I submit he is not on trial here for his past.
而是因为谋杀唐纳德·科瓦奇
He is on trial for the murders of Donald Kovack
和埃迪·阿朗佐
and Eddie Alonzo.
单排扣
Single-breasted...
淡蓝色还是淡黄色
Light blue or cream.
蓝色
Blue.
亚麻布
Linen.
单个口袋
S-single pocket.
要立遗嘱吗  找麦吉尔
你好
Hello, there.
我叫詹姆斯·麦吉尔  是名律师
James McGill, attorney at law.
上午感觉怎么样
How are you this fine morning?
-还不错  你呢  -非常好
- I'm just fine. And how about you? - Very good.
别耍赖哦
Play fair.
地上掉了什么
Oh, what do we got here?
知道了
I see.
这一块想逃跑
A piece is trying to get away.
果冻吃得开心
Enjoy the jello.
要吃完哦
Get to the bottom.
慢着  这里谁是银行家
Wait. Who's the banker here?
我只想和银行家说话  在这呢
That's the only one I want to talk to. There he is.
你好吗
How are ya?
我很好  你手劲像小伙子
I'm good. Whoa! What a grip, young man!
轻点握
Yeah, watch out.
我这只手要写遗嘱
That's my will-writing hand.
好
Okay.
女士们好  今天很美
Hello, ladies. You look beautiful today.
那边还好吗
All right over there?
我很好  别耍赖哦
Very good. Play fair.
不玩钱
Ah, no betting.
慢着  你是维罗妮卡·莱克吗
Oh, wait a second. Is that Veronica Lake?
抱一个  美人
Give me a hug, beautiful.
你今天气色不错
Yes. You look great today.
别出千  药都吃了  别藏起来
All right, no cheating. No hiding the tablet.
这里在干什么
Oh, what do we have here?
他在这呢  房间[布思]里的人
Hey, there he is -- the man in the booth,
约翰·威尔克斯·布思[刺杀林肯者]
John Wilkes Booth,
布思·塔金顿[小说家]
Booth Tarkington.
在看什么呢
What you reading there?
《停车场认证规则全解》吗
"The complete annotated book of rules for parking validation"?
不是
No.
停车场认证规则非常简单
The rules for parking validation are actually pretty simple.
大部分人一次就懂
Most people get it on the first try.
你要知道肯定很开心
Well, you'll be pleased to know
我拿到了足量的贴纸
I have the requisite stickers.
有什么好开心的
Well, be still my heart.
然后
And...
再给你一张这个
you can have this, as well.
我现在主攻老年法
I'm doing Elder law now.
要立遗嘱吗  找麦吉尔
Need a will? Call McGill.
打我电话  如果你...
So, give me a call if you, uh --
如果你碰巧认识老人
uh, if, uh, you happen to know any elders.
今晚愉快
Good night.
今晚差不到哪里去
Couldn't have a bad one if I tried.
-晚安  -晚安
- Good night. - Night.
你怎么在过道里
Out here in the hall and everything?
别傻了
Don't be so silly.
反正又没人
Well, there's nobody around.
就算有人
Oh, but you never can tell
-你也不知道  -我要进去
- when there's someone around. - Then I'll come in.
不  丹  我要是你就不进去
Oh, no, Dan, I wouldn't come in if I were you.
我们真要迟到了
Really, we're going to be awfully late.
别害羞  露西
Well, don't be bashful, Lucy.
我没害羞  但我从没亲过你
Well, I'm not bashful, but I've never kissed you before,
我觉得这地方不合适
and I don't think this is exactly the place.
天  要是你知道我有多爱你
Gosh, if you knew how crazy I am about you,
你就不会犹豫了  我夜不能寐
you wouldn't hesitate -- I can't sleep nights.
为什么不喝点热牛奶
Oh, why don't you take some hot milk?
我觉得自己爱上你了  因为...
I guess I must be in love, 'cause it started right --
离家很远吧
Long way from home, aren't you?
我们都是
You and me both.